Guide to the Kermit Carlyle Parsons papers, circa 1945-1999
Parsons, Kermit Carlyle papers, circa 1945-1999
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Kermit Carlyle Parsons papers, circa 1945-1999
15-2-1428
Kermit C. Parsons, 1927-
121 cubic feet, plus oversize material
Manuscripts, typescripts, printer's proofs, index cards, publications, student papers, files, and other papers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes manuscripts, publications, files, and other papers related to Kermit C. Parsons' career as a planner and as professor of architecture at Cornell University.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell professor of Architecture and City and Regional Planning, and Dean of the College of Architecture, Art and Planning.
Born on July 15, 1927, in Cleveland, Ohio, Kermit Carlyle Parsons earned a Bachelors of Architecture from Miami University in Ohio in 1951 and a Masters of Regional Planning from Cornell University in 1953, during which time he received a University Fellowship in Architecture. After earning his degree from Cornell, he worked as a city planner for the Cleveland (Ohio) City Planning Commission and as a city planner for the Cleveland Metropolitan Housing Authority. Parsons joined the Cornell faculty in 1957, becoming Associate Professor in 1960 and Professor in 1965. He was named dean of the College of Architecture, Art and Planning in 1971, serving until 1980. He returned to teaching until 1985, when he became the director of the Cornell-in-Washington program, a position he held until 1988. Parsons retired from the University in 1999.
During his career, he served as a consultant on city and university planning projects in New York State and elsewhere. He authored books including Writings of Clarence S. Stein: Architect of the Planned Community and The Cornell Campus: A History of its Planning and Development. He was a co-author of An Annotated Bibliography on University Planning and Development and, with David Schuyler, he edited the book From Garden City to Green City: The Legacy of Ebenezer Howard. Parsons died on December 9, 1999.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records related to Parson's career as Cornell Professor of Architecture and Dean of the School of Art, Architecture and Regional Planning. Research and manuscripts on topics such as Clarence Stein, Nathaniel Owings, and Cornell History. Records from Parsons' role as a faculty member and administrator, including syllabi, course-related documents, thesis material for advisees, and administrative documentation and reports from City and Regional Planning (CRP) and Art, Architecture and Urban Planning (AAP). Records of Parsons broader professional work include documentation of his consulting work, and of his involvement in professional organizations. Also, consulting materials related to on-campus projects, including the renovation of Sage Hall. Includes correspondence, photographs, maps and plans.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Series II. Nathaniel Owings Archives Project
Materials Parsons gathered to create a research collection documenting Nathaniel Owings' contributions to urban development. Parsons was to write a book titled, Nathaniel Owings and the Freeways: The Baltimore Wars, on Owings' work in Baltimore on designing a new freeway system. The archives project was completed in 1983, but although Parsons completed several drafts, he did not publish a book.
Project Correspondence
Correspondence about the Owings archives project and the Baltimore Wars book project.
Baltimore
Relates to the project by the firm Skidmore, Owings and Merrill (SOM) to design a freeway system in Baltimore, Maryland.
Other Projects
Correspondence and reports on other Owings projects.
Series III. Research and Consulting
Parsons’ research for his book projects, including articles by others, and drafts of his manuscripts. Also includes his consulting work for outside organizations.
Clarence Stein research files
Research for and drafts of Parsons’ book Writings of Clarence S. Stein: Architect of the Planned Community
Cornell History
Research for and drafts of Parsons’ book The Cornell Campus: A History of its Planning and Development
Consulting
Includes consulting projects for outside universities and cities, both domestic and foreign. Also includes consulting materials for the Korean World Bank.
Series IV. Cornell University Faculty and Administrative Files
Materials associated with Parsons' function as a faculty member and administrator at Cornell. Also includes material associated with events and life at Cornell.
City and Regional Planning (CRP) Administration
Student files and departmental correspondence and memoranda.
Art, Architecture and Planning (AAP) Administration
Includes administrative materials that precede and coincide with Parsons’ tenure as dean, as well as later documents.
Planning for Cornell/Cornell Consulting
Studies and correspondence related to architecture and planning for the Cornell campus. Includes material on the controversy over remodeling Sage Hall.
Coursework
Syllabi and documentation for courses Parsons taught at Cornell.
Advising and Theses
Includes theses written by Parsons' students.
Series V. Professional
Professional Organizations and Conferences
Material from Parsons’ participation in professional organizations such as the American Institute of Planners, and materials from conferences at which he was present or participated.
Professional involvement and history
Additional material from and about Parsons career, including notes and research from his time as a student. Also includes his datebooks.
Series VI. Multimedia
Series VII. Oversize
SUBJECTS
Names:
Parsons, Kermit C. (Kermit Carlyle), 1927-; Parsons, Kermit C. (Kermit Carlyle), 1927- Cornell campus.; Parsons, Kermit C. (Kermit Carlyle), 1927- History of campus planning at Cornell.; Parsons, Kermit C. (Kermit Carlyle), 1927- Quad on the hill.; Bryant, Stewart.; D'Alesandro, Thomas J.; McKeldin, Theodore R. (Theodore Roosevelt), 1900-1974; Owings, Nathaniel Alexander, 1903-; Schaefer, William Donald.; Skidmore, Owings & Merrill.; Urban Design Concept Associates.; Cornell University--Faculty.; Cornell University--Planning.
Subjects:
City planning.; Campus planning--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Universities and colleges--New York (State)--Ithaca--Buildings--Planning.; Architects.; City planners.; College teachers.; City planning--Maryland--Baltimore.; City planning--Ohio--Cleveland.; City planning--Indiana--Gary.; City planning--California--Irvine.; City planning--New York (State)--Utica.; City planning--New York (State)--Broome County.; City planning--New York (State)--Tompkins County.; Express highways--Maryland--Baltimore.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIAL
Kelly, Parsons, Canfield and Stein, Planning Consultants. Ithaca Urban Renewal Plans, #2776.
K.C. Parsons publications collection, #6691.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Letter from Robert Kennedy, 1964 (Box 113, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous invitations and postcards, 1965-1978 (Box 113, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1969 (Box 113, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1970s, 1992 (Box 113, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence and newsletters, 1970-92 (Box 113, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1977 (Box 113, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1978 (Box 113, Folder 11)
  - Thank you card, 1979 (Box 113, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Files, 1978-1999 (Box 114, Folder 1)
  - Personal Correspondence, 1980 (Box 114, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1982-97 (Box 114, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1982-2001 (Box 114, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence regarding Nathanial Owings, 1984 (Box 114, Folder 5)
  - Letter from Janice Parsons, 1986 (Box 114, Folder 6)
  - Cornell Correspondence, 1986-1999 (Box 114, Folder 7)
  - Letters of Appreciation, 1988-1998 (Box 114, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence regarding Parson's Publication, 1992-1993 (Box 114, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1992-1998 (Box 114, Folder 10)
  - Hans Mammen Correspondence, 1993 (Box 114, Folder 11)
  - KCP student correspondence, 1994 (Box 114, Folder 12)
  - Letter to Parsons from Jan Parsons, 1995 (Box 114, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence regarding paper on Clarence Stein, 1996 (Box 114, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence regarding Larry Anderson Manuscript on Benton MacKaye, 1996 (Box 114, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Cornell Correspondence, 1997 (Box 114, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence about consulting work and projects at Cornell, 1997-2000 (Box 114, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence between Kieren Killen and Parsons, 1998 (Box 114, Folder 18)
  - Miller and Mervin Correspondence, 1998-1999 (Box 114, Folder 19)
  - Ithaca Postcards, undated (Box 114, Folder 20)
- Series II. Nathaniel Owings Archive Project
  - Project Correspondence
    - Baltimore Wars funding, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - BW project correspondence and notes, including Fells Point chronology and narrative summary, 1980s (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Nathaniel Owings, history of Baltimore project, 1980s (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence and notes - Nathanial Owings archive project, early 1980s (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - Owings project statements (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - SOM research project proposals, 1979-1980 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Owings-personal and other (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Baltimore
    - Drafts, Outlines and Notes
      - Baltimore Wars (?) draft - chapters 11-20 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Working file/ outlines, charts (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Baltimore Wars table of contents, introduction and notes (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Baltimore Wars table of contents, outlines and notes, circa 1983 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Baltimore Wars notes, "cast of characters", circa 1984 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - Baltimore Wars, partial manuscript, chapters 1-12, March 1984 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Baltimore Wars, partial manuscript, chapters 12-17, undated (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Baltimore Wars, partial manuscript, introduction-chapter 11, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - Fells Point narrative summary (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - Baltimore Wars, chapter one draft (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - Baltimore Wars chapter drafts (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - Baltimore Wars, partial manuscript, chapters 1-14, September 1985 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      - Baltimore Wars, 3rd draft manuscript, April 1990 (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - Baltimore Wars drafts, chapters 1-11 (Box 16, Folder 14)
      - Baltimore Wars drafts, chapters 12-21 (Box 16, Folder 15)
      - Baltimore Wars drafts, chapters 16-20 (Box 16, Folder 16)
      - Draft - Owings book manuscript, December 1980-February 1981 (Box 16, Folder 17-18)
      - Nathaniel Owings and the Freeways: The Baltimore Wars, partial manuscript, chapters 1-12, March 1984 (Box 16, Folder 19)
      - Baltimore Wars draft transcription, January 16, 1981 (Box 16, Folder 20)
      - Baltimore Wars draft, pages 54-82 (Box 16, Folder 21)
      - Baltimore Wars drafts, chapters 1-2 (Box 16, Folder 22)
      - Baltimore Wars drafts, chapters 1-4, April 1982 (Box 16, Folder 23)
      - Baltimore Wars drafts, chapters 1-6 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Baltimore Wars drafts, chapters 3-4 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Baltimore Wars miscellaneous chapter drafts (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Drafts of Baltimore Wars paper, 1999 (Box 17, Folder 4-5)
      - Baltimore Wars drafts, early chapters, 1981-1982 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Baltimore Wars drafts, 1980-1981 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Baltimore Wars introduction draft, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Notes and timelines (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Baltimore Wars drafts: introduction, chapter 1, 1984, 1990, undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Baltimore Wars second draft manuscript, chapters 1-5, January 1990 (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - BW drafts - chapters 14-21, circa 1984-1985 (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - BW drafts - chapters 16-18, September 1985 (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - BW drafts - introduction, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - BW drafts - chapters 13-18, undated (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - BW drafts - Fells Point, undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - BW chapter drafts and notes, undated (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - Baltimore Wars, 3rd draft manuscript, April 1990 (Box 17, Folder 18-19)
      - Baltimore Wars, partial manuscript, chapters 1-9, 13, 20, no date (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - Outline of chapters, March 19, 1984 (Box 17, Folder 21)
      - Chapter drafts, September 17, 1989 (?) (Box 17, Folder 22)
      - Baltimore Wars drafts, chapters 1-9, 1984-1985 (Box 17, Folder 23)
      - Baltimore Wars drafts, chapters 10-14, 1984-1985 (Box 17, Folder 24)
      - BW drafts, "Owings' Great Stroke" and "A 3-C Victory" (Box 17, Folder 25)
      - BW chapter edits, 1984-1985 (Box 17, Folder 26-27)
      - BW chapter outline, cast of characters, circa 1984 (Box 17, Folder 28)
      - BW draft - chapter 16 "Opposition/The MAD Coalition" (Box 17, Folder 29)
      - Baltimore Wars draft - chapters 1-10 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Baltimore Wars 3rd draft manuscript - chapters 1-17, April 1990 (Box 18, Folder 2-3)
      - Baltimore Wars draft - chapters 16-23 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Baltimore Wars drafts - various chapters in 20s and 30s, circa 1984 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - BW drafts - "Owings' Great Stroke" (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - BW drafts - chapter 23 "D'Alesandro Decides" (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Baltimore Wars 3rd draft manuscript - table of contents, introduction, April 1990 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Baltimore Wars 2nd draft manuscript - introduction, chapter 1, January 1990 (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Baltimore Wars draft - chapters 1-12, 15 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - BW chapter edits (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - UDCA/Maryland Highway Dept. notes; Agnew scandal clippings, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Articles and research notes (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Research Files
      - Nathaniel Owings' day calendars, 1953-1955; 2 volumes (Box 43)
      - Chapter 4-5: UDCA January-May 4, 1967; Southwest study (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Chapter 6: UDCA/DCT January-April 15, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Chapter 7: UDCA/DCT/Owings speech, NAO, Woolf flap, April 15-May 5, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Chapter 8: UDCA (post-flap, pre-contract), May-September 24, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Chapter 9: UDCA, September 24 - December 1, 1967 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Documents for Chapter 10: Community planning, Rosemont, Franklin Mulberry, January - August 19, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 6-7)
      - Documents for Chapter 11: Community relations (part 1), December 1967 - August 15, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Documents for Chapter 11: Community relations (part 2), December 1967 - May 1968 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Documents for Chap.13: SOM, San Francisco, Washington, D.C., August 24 - Sept 25, 1968 (Box 25, Folder 10-11)
      - Norman Klein (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - UDCA-community relations, relocation, housing, implementation, April-August 1968 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - UDCA, May-June 1968 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - UDCA progress reports, January 1968-February 1969 (Box 25, Folder 15)
      - UDCA, January 1968 (Box 25, Folder 16)
      - UDCA-key documents, January-April 1968 (Box 25, Folder 17)
      - UDCA-key documents, July-August 1968 (Box 25, Folder 18)
      - Baltimore-Department of Transportation regulations, March-April 1968 (Box 25, Folder 19)
      - UDCA - segment design, finance schedule, management, December 1967 - 1968 (Box 25, Folder 20)
      - West Team - Leakin Park, 1967-1968 (Box 25, Folder 21)
      - UDCA, December 1967 (Box 25, Folder 22)
      - UDCA-project management, 1967-1968 (Box 25, Folder 23)
      - Concept Review Committee minutes - documents submitted as court exhibits (Box 25, Folder 24)
      - UDCA-Owings, April 1967 - January 1971 (Box 25, Folder 25)
      - UDCA-community relations, relocation, housing, implementation, September-December 1968 (Box 25, Folder 26)
      - UDCA and SRC documents - chapter12, December 1967 - August 1968 (Box 25, Folder 27)
      - UDCA-key documents - chapter 14, October 1968 - January 1969 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - UDCA-key documents, September-November 1968 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - UDCA-Owings CPHA speech, documents for chapter 14, September 24, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Segment 5-Fells Point (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Bryant papers-Fells Point, segment 5, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Fells Point, segment 5, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - Rosemont, system, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - City wide data, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 8)
      - System - Leakin Park, Ft. McHenry Bridge (Box 26, Folder 9)
      - East Team (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - Center Team, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 11)
      - Franklin, Mulberry (Box 26, Folder 12)
      - Overall systems design - signage, structural (Box 26, Folder 13)
      - Overall systems design - acoustics, landscape (Box 26, Folder 14)
      - Overall systems design - lighting (Box 26, Folder 15)
      - Overall systems design - general, alignment (Box 26, Folder 16)
      - Roadway signage correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 26, Folder 17)
      - Audiotape transcription (original and copy) (Box 26, Folder 18)
      - Articles (Box 26, Folder 19)
      - Reports, correspondence, minutes, 1968-1970 (Box 26, Folder 20)
      - Joint development, 1971 (Box 26, Folder 21)
      - Joint development correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 26, Folder 22)
      - Joint development correspondence, January-July 1969 (Box 26, Folder 23)
      - Early chapters - key documents not used (Box 26, Folder 24)
      - Segment One design, 1969-1970 (Box 26, Folder 25)
      - Joint development - point V reports (Box 26, Folder 26)
      - Documents on Segment 10 (Box 26, Folder 27)
      - Documents on Segments 1 and 4 (Box 26, Folder 28)
      - Reference materials (Box 26, Folder 29)
      - Background/history on expressway planning (1942-1968) (Box 26, Folder 30)
      - Joint Development Implementation Study, Baltimore Planning Commission, June 1971 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Baltimore - Quad Avenue industrial park, circa 1968 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Baltimore - UDCA, relocation, housing, 1966-1970 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Baltimore - UDCA, non-residential correspondence, circa 1970 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Excerpts from the Baltimore Downtown Renaissance, The Future of Downtown Baltimore (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Report on 3-A planning status and history (Box 27, Folder 6)
      - Segment 6-Sharp Leadenhall (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - Segment 7-Southwest (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - Leakin Park-Segment 9, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - Leakin Park-Segment 9, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 10-11)
      - Segment 13-Gwynnes Falls (Box 27, Folder 12)
      - Fort McHenry-Segment 14 (Box 27, Folder 13)
      - Proof of Gwynns Falls Bypass Corridor Study, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 14)
      - Fort McHenry bypass, Point III report proof (Box 27, Folder 15)
      - Overviews (Box 27, Folder 16)
      - Preliminary Outline of Joint & Collateral Development Complexes for the Maryland State Roads Commission Interstate System in Baltimore City. (draft) UDCA, September 26, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 17)
      - Stew Bryant miscellaneous/(important?); Agnew, 1968-1973 (Box 27, Folder 18)
      - MAD legal hearing materials, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 19)
      - UDCA correspondence-Joseph Axelrod, 1969-1971 (Box 27, Folder 20)
      - Klein's notes-DOT, urban transportation study (Box 27, Folder 21)
      - UDCA consultants, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 22)
      - Interim Submission: Design Criteria for the Baltimore Interstate Highways. UDCA, April 1968 (Box 27, Folder 23)
      - Correspondence and articles - UDCA and Baltimore, 1968-1970 (Box 27, Folder 24)
      - Post 3-A System, segment research, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 25)
      - 3-A System, 1968 (Box 27, Folder 26)
      - Baltimore Planning Commission newsletter, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 27)
      - Roadway design (Box 27, Folder 28)
      - Correspondence - Owings; Marcou, O'Leary and Associates, 1969-1970 (Box 27, Folder 29)
      - System segments and organizational chart (Box 27, Folder 30)
      - Correspondence, clippings, 1969-1970, 1982 (Box 27, Folder 31)
      - Design Criteria for Baltimore Interstate Highways: Supplementary Acoustical Report (Revised). Grant S. Anderson (Bolt, Beranek and Newman Inc.) [submitted to UDCA], December 1970 (Box 27, Folder 32)
      - UDCA: Segment design examples, Central Team, 1967-1968 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - UDCA: Segment design examples, Middle Branch, Southwest Team, 1967-1970 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - UDCA: Segment design examples, West Team, Leakin Park, 1967-1968 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - UDCA: Segment design examples, Southwest Team 6, 7, 8 and 12, 1967-1968 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - UDCA: Segment design examples, East Team, 1967-1968 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - UDCA (DCT), Rogers/Funk, 1966 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Corridor, newsletter of the Interstate Division for Baltimore City, circa 1970 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Landscaping plans, Segment 1 (UDCA), March 1970 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - State Roads Commission, segment correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - State Roads Commission - 3-A approval, expressways correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 28, Folder 10)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence and reports, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 11)
      - Segment 1 (Box 28, Folder 12)
      - Segment 2 (Box 28, Folder 13)
      - Segments 3 and 4 (Box 28, Folder 14)
      - UDCA progress reports, December 1968 - November 1970 (Box 28, Folder 15-16)
      - Baltimore City Council proceedings on East-West expressway (transcripts), 1972 (Box 28, Folder 17-18)
      - Transit Coordination: Baltimore Interstate Highway System. UDCA., 1970 (Box 28, Folder 19)
      - Project Description. UDCA., December 1969 (Box 28, Folder 20)
      - Technical Report No. 2. History of Project Planning for the 3-A System and I-83, 1942-1977. U.S. Dept. of Transportation., November 1978 (Box 28, Folder 21)
      - Compilation of UDCA reports (Box 28, Folder 22)
      - Consultants (Box 28, Folder 23)
      - Guides and outlines (Box 28, Folder 24)
      - Contracts, 1969-1970 (Box 28, Folder 25)
      - Franklin-Mulberry - Segment 10 (Box 28, Folder 26)
      - Community Profile: Franklin-Mulberry Corridor., January 17, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 27)
      - Final Environmental Impact Statement. City Boulevard in Baltimore City, Maryland. U.S. Dept. of Transportation., April 1977 (Box 28, Folder 28)
      - 3-A Interstate and Boulevard System Summary map, April 1979 (Box 28, Folder 29)
      - Boulevard-Segment 11 (Box 28, Folder 28)
      - City Planning Reviewing Group - meeting on Segments 1 and 7, May 28, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 29)
      - Newsletter article-SOM, UDCTA, planning dept. (Box 28, Folder 30)
      - Newspapers articles - chronology of the Urban Design Concept Team, 1966-1969 (Box 28, Folder 31)
      - Report outline - Transportation Network for Baltimore, July 1968 (Box 28, Folder 32)
      - Rosemont, Segment 10-documents used for Chapter 22, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
      - Documents from "old" Rosemont chapter file, 1968-1969 (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Images, plans, and diagrams - Baltimore, UDCA project, undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Rosemont Bypass Study. UDCA, May 1969 (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Rosemont By-Pass Phase II Report - First Draft Revision. UDCA, March 17, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - Information on the alternate routes for I-170 for residents participating in the Corridor Location Hearing, August 6, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Location Study Report - I-170 - Rosemont Bypass, Baltimore, Maryland. Maryland State Roads Commission, Interstate Division for Baltimore City., August 12, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Baltimore reports, 1968-1970 (Box 30, Folder 9)